A Guide to the Papers of the Langhorne Family, 1899-1984
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Langhorne Family 1899-1984
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10758
This collection contains ca. 330 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library on April 18, 1988 by Phyllis Langhorne Draper of Charlottesville, Virginia; Harry Forsyth Langhorne of Lowesville, Virginia; and, William Keene Langhorne of Portola Valley, California.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of ca. 330 items, 1899-1984, n.d., pertaining chiefly to the family of Chiswell Dabney Langhorne (1843-1918) and his wife, "Nanaire," the former Nancy Witcher Keene (1848-1904). Among their children were five daughters: Irene (Mrs. Charles Dana Gibson); Elizabeth (Mrs. Thomas Moncure Perkins); Nora (Mrs. Paul Phipps, later Mrs. Maurice Flynn); Phyllis (Mrs. Robert H. Brand); and, Nancy Witcher (Mrs. Robert Gould Shaw, later Lady Astor, wife of Waldorf Astor); and sons: Keene (married Sadie Reynolds); Harry (married Genevieve Peyton); and, William Henry (married Edith Forsyth).
Included are essays by Nancy Lancaster (formerly Nancy Keene Perkins Tree) about Chiswell Dabney Langhorne, Nancy Witcher Keene Langhorne, and "Mirador," Greenwood. There are also electrostatic copies of letters chiefly written to Nancy Lancaster from her Langhorne aunts and uncles, Nora, Irene, and William Henry "Buck" as well as from servants at "Mirador," such as Stewart Wood, Ann Broady, Lucy Ann (Wood) Hughes, and Callie Brown. There is also a copy of a letter to Lady Astor from Angus McDonald. These letters are concerned with personal and family matters.
In addition, there are many photographs of members of the Astor, Forsyth, Gibson, and Langhorne families. Photographs of Lady Astor include her pictured with University of Virginia President John Lloyd Newcomb, Sir Samuel Hoarse, her husband Waldorf Astor and their children, and Irene Langhorne Gibson. There is also a photograph of David Astor and Alice Moncure taken with Prime Minister of England Margaret Thatcher. Other photographs include ones of the Langhorne family home, "Mirador," and the family servants.
Printed material re Lady Astor includes information on her private and public life as well as articles relating to Lord Astor, Irene Langhorne Gibson (1933, 1956), Elizabeth Dabney Langhorne Lewis (1942), George Bernard Shaw (1951), and remembrances of Lady Astor and her childhood home, "Mirador."
There are two Forsyth family scrapbooks, 1899 and 1901, containing photographs; and, two Langhorne family scrapbooks, 1929 and 1919-1939, containing photographs and printed material. The oversize scrapbook, 1919-1939, is available on microfilm.
Contents List
- Essays on members of the Langhorne family by Nancy Lancaster n.d. (Box 1)
- Letters to Nancy Lancaster (formerly Nancy Keene Perkins Tree) from Langhorne family members 1936-1943, n.d. (Box 1)
- Letters to Nancy Lancaster (formerly Nancy Keene Perkins Tree) from "Mirador" Servants 1930-1957, n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of Lady Astor (nee Nancy Witcher Langhorne), and family and friends 1922, 1946, n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of the Astor, Forsyth, Gibson, and Langhorne families, and miscellaneous n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of Edith Agnes Forsyth, William Henry "Buck" Langhorne, and family and friends n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of Children and Descendants of Chiswell Dabney Langhorne and Nancy Witcher Keene Langhorne n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of Chiswell Dabney Langhorne, Nancy Witcher Keene Langhorne, and family and friends ca. 1905, n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of "Mirador," Greenwood n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of Servants of the Langhorne family at "Mirador," Greenwood n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs of the BBC movie, "Lady Astor" 1982 (Box 1)
- Printed Material re Lady Astor 1907-1984, n.d., 3 folders (Box 1)
- Printed Material re the Astors and Langhornes 1932-1952 (Box 1)
- Social Papers pertaining to Lady Astor 1929-1964 (Box 1)
- Forsyth family scrapbook of photographs 1899 (Box 1)
- Forsyth family scrapbook of photographs 1901 (Box 2)
- Langhorne family scrapbook 1929, n.d. (Box 2)
- Langhorne family scrapbook 1919-1939, n.d., Microfilm